Hi everyone, today I would like to talk about Creator Connections, an easy to use tool that's designed
to generate additional sales for you.
It's under Amazon's advertising and brand content.
There are a few easy steps to set it up.
The first tip I want to give is the length of
the campaign.
I would usually start a campaign for at least 3 to 6 months long because that
tells the creators that they actually have enough time to submit content and enough time
for them to generate sales for you.
The second would be the budget.
Honestly, I would really
suggest maximize your budget number.
It can go up to crazy number.
Usually, I only ended
up using a fraction of that budget, but again, that sends a very positive signal to creators
that you are in Creator Connections for a long haul and you have enough budget for your
campaign.
And then the third would be commission rate.
I would suggest starting from 10% at
least.
Depending on how competitive your niche is, say my niche is super competitive.
Sometimes
I go up to 20% as a commission rate.
And then fourth would be the campaign brief.
The information
in there would often be referred by the creator in their videos.
So they're important, but
don't make it longer than a paragraph because anything longer than that, a lot of creators
they would just tune out.
And then when creators messages you for samples, I usually ask my
VA to ask them for links of at least one of their social media platforms so that we can
check engagement.
Not just the number of followers they have, but how many comments, how many
likes, and how often do they post on their platform?
Those are all metrics for us to
determine if this creator is a good fit for us.
And once they submitted the content and
generate some sales for you, definitely, definitely generate a list of effective creators who
has converted for you and who has submitted good content that fits your brand, you could
see it from the dashboard what kind of content they submitted.
There is a link to that.
So
there's really a lot of information you can see to determine how a creator can help you
generate sales the next time when you have a new campaign, definitely send messages to
invite those effective creators first and really prioritize them in terms of communicating
and sending samples.
So that's my list of tips for Creator Connections.
Happy selling.